JOSEPH FITZSIMMONS

WEB DEVELOPER



DENVER, CO



314.304.8268



joe@hoseb.com

SKILLS

- HTML / HTML5
- CSS / CSS3 / SASS / Compass
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Require JS
- JSHint
- Foundation
- AJAX / FLEX
- XML / XSL
- JSON / SOAP
- Jira
- Git / Subversion
- Relational Database Concepts: PL/SQL, MySQL, MS SQL
- eCommerce: Demandware
- Adobe Suite: Photoshop, Flash, Dreamweaver
- CMS and Enterprise Apps: WordPress, Drupal, SharePoint
- Various IDEs: Eclipse, Visual Studio
- PHP
- SEO
- Analytics: Adobe Analytics, Google, Tealium Tag Management

EDUCATION & AWARDS

Vatterott College

St. Louis, MO. 2004-2006 Associates of Science: Information Systems

Demandware

DW Developer Certified in 2013

IABC

Bronze Quill Award 2010

Step Two Designs

Intranet Innovation Award 2008

PROFILE

Web developer with nine years' experience creating and managing sites for major companies in both the financial and retail sectors. Excels in meeting simultaneous long and short-term deadlines and ushering projects from inception to delivery. Shared roles in multiple top-down redesigns for global sites, one of which exceeded an optimistic quarterly sales goal of 15 million dollars for NewBalance.com.

EXPERIENCE

ST. LOUIS, MO.

NEW BALANCE eCommerce Web Developer

06/2013 - present

- Develops and documents technical solutions in response to enhancement and optimization requests regarding New Balance's eCommerce websites.
- Participates and leads coding of solutions and assists with quality assurance activities including unit testing, system testing and solution validation.
- Performs daily builds and promotion of code to the development environment for subsequent testing and offers leadership to entire development team.
- Ensures best practices are established and followed and assists lessexperienced developers with technical challenges.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Intranet Developer 03/2009 - 05/2013

- Was responsible for the implementation and coding of all CSS, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML for the Scottrade Intranet.
- Was the point of contact for all projects and applications and reviewed all Work Requests from varying departments within Scottrade.
- Worked with third party vendors to consume API's, track site analytics, improve SEO and site usability.
- Marketed, promoted and branded website using style guides, banners and general promotions and streamlined processes with reusable pages, templates and styles.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Intranet Administrator and Content Engineer 12/2006 - 03/2009

- Was involved in applications from development to production and facilitated QA, UAT and Regression Testing for enhancements.
- Gathered functional requirements, created technical specifications and maintained competitive architecture with other businesses.
- · Administrated permissions and roles for secured content.
- · Answered support calls and delegated responsibilities to co-workers.

ST. LOUIS, MO.

SCOTTRADE

Corporate Communications Intern 03/2006 - 12/2006

- · Assisted in conceptualization and execution of high-level technical plans.
- · Consulted with business groups to clarify requirements and feasibility.
- Helped to provide technical solutions and participated in discussions to expand knowledge of systems and processes.
- · Assisted with technical support and triaged issues as needed.